放下武器
Put down your weapon.
我有充分证据来判你有罪
I find it incumbent you see the inside of a cell.
我正在找人  那家伙叫 林肯・布伦斯
I'm looking for someone, guy named Lincoln Burrows.
那家伙杀了副总统的兄弟
Man killed the VP's brother.
为什么你这么着急想见布伦斯
Why you want to see Burrows so bad, anyhow?
因为他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
-我正想法把你弄出去  -这不可能
-I'm getting you out.  -It's impossible.
如果我是这里的设计人 就有可能
Not if you designed the place,it isn't.
-你看过这儿的设计图纸了   -不仅如此
-You've seen the blueprints.  -Better than that.
我把它纹在身上了
I've got'em on me.
你查到是谁想害他么
You find out who's trying to bury him.
-没人想害他  -那证据是伪造的
-Nobody's trying to bury him.  -The evidence was cooked.
有个律师在多管闲事
There's a lawyer poking around.
对任何危害到我们的人都是可以消失的
Anyone that's a threat is expendable.
我要杀了那人渣
I'm gonna kill that scum.
不能那样  如果你杀了他 你就毁了大家逃出去的希望
You won't. You kill him, you kill our express ticket out of here.
你来这儿干吗  玛丽克鲁兹 呢
you doing here? Where's Maricruz?
她现在和我在一起
She's with me now.
听着  我必须回那儿去
Fish, I gotta be back in.
尼克・萨维恩 的那个司法案子
Nick Savrinn with Project Justice.
我的老板认为林肯的案子 已经没有再跟进的必要了
My boss may not think Lincoln's case is worth looking into,
但我可不这么想
but I do.
我们什么时候动手
When do we get started?
打穿这堵墙只是第一步
Getting through this wall is just the beginning.
这堵墙和外面还隔着好多呢
There's a whole lot of real estate in between here and the outside walls.
这是份移送的文件
That is a transfer request.
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德明早会被转到其他监狱去了
Michael Scofield is getting shipped out tomorrow.
我想你们是为 迈克尔・斯科菲尔德 的那份移交申请来的吧
I assume this is about your transfer request for Michael Scofield.
更确切地说 为什么你拒绝
More specifically, why you denied it.
听着  克勒曼先生 我可没跑到你家
Look, Mr Kellerman, do I come to your house
然后对你家里家具摆设指手画脚
and tell you where to put your furniture?
我们只是帮你一个小忙而已
We're just asking for professional courtesy.
我这个小小的州监狱可承受不了 你们联邦政府的好意
But you're asking for a federal courtesy in a state penitentiary.
多数在你位置上的人
Most people on your position would be happy
都会很乐意这件事让别人接手的
to have a body taken off their hands.
惩罚那些人是我的责任
These men are my responsibility.
从他们踏进那儿起
From the minute they walk through those walls
直到他们还清了社会责任为止
to the time they've paid their debt to society,
我都会对他们负责
I'm responsible for them.
也就是说除非 斯科菲尔德 他做了什么我还不知道的事
Which means that unless he's done something I don't know about,
他就将一直在我的监管下待在这儿
he is gonna stay here at Fox River under my watch.
普柏 先生 在我们的调查中
Mr Pope, in our line of work,
刚好发现一些其他人还不知道的事
we've discovered that just about everyone has done something that someone doesn't know about.
这是什么
What's this?
目前看 还只是一段过去的事情而已
Right now, just a piece of history.
至于是不是将会变成现在时 就看你怎么做了
Whether it becomes a current event,now, that's up to you.
我妻子已经知道 托雷多 的事了
My wife already knows about Toledo.
是么
Does she really?
你是个聪明人  监狱长先生
You're a smart man, Warden.
我相信如果你仔细看
I'm sure if you look hard enough,
你肯定能找到一个原因来解释
you could find a reason why Michael Scofield's presence is no longer required
为什么 迈克尔・斯科菲尔德 不再需要呆在这儿了
at this particular correctional facility.
这儿需要更多的管子  长官
I need some more PVC here, boss.
-长官  -这个很常见 布伦斯
-Boss?  -Sure thing, Burrows.
但  听着  我可不想挨个找碎片去
But, hey, I don't wanna check for splinters.
-我希望每一片都有去处   -当然
-I want every piece accounted for.  -Sure.
我发现里面有袋撕破了的化肥
I got a ripped fertilizer bag inside.
嘿  你
Hey, you!
就是你
You!
去把里面清理干净
Get in there and clean it up
否则里面太难闻了
before this whole place starts smelling like San Juan.
嘿  他正朝这儿走来
OK, he's on his way.
能告诉我究竟发生什么了吗
Do you mind telling me what this is all about?
这些就都是要越狱的
These are the guys we're breaking out with.
我可不这么想  小子
I don't think so, fish.
之前我们可不是这么说的
That was not our agreement.
我可不想和这些
I'm not gonna work with this
-和这些疯子一起  -你再说阿
-crazy rhino.  -Keep pushing it, John.
是的 我就要说
Yeah, I keep pushing it, you know. Huh?
那你能做些什么
What's your deal, man?
再动我的兄弟试试  我就会让你知道
Touch my brother again and I'll show you.
兄弟  你的兄弟
Brother? Your brother?
我们只有几分钟的时间
We've only got a few minutes.
我们是用它来互相扯皮
We're gonna spend them spitting on each other,
还是一起谈点正事儿
or are we gonna talk some business?
我们现在必须作出一个决定
The reason we're all here today is we have a decision to make.
英格力士  费兹  还是博西
English, Fitz, or Percy.
如果我们想成功越狱
If we're gonna pull this off,
我们就得在这几个中选一个
we need to take one of them out.
你想让我们告诉你选哪个么
And you want us to tell you which one?
我只是想让你们帮我想清楚
I just want you to help me get to them.
-我会作出判断  -你疯了 你知道吗
-I'll take it from there.  -You're crazy.
-我只需要五分钟   -你连五秒钟都没有
-All I need is five minutes. -You won't get five seconds.
我以为你什么都搞定了
I thought you had everything worked out.
我们不是要逃出一家连锁店而已 先生们
We're not breaking out of a Jamba Juice.
不仅仅需要挖几个洞
It's gonna take more than digging a few holes.
这里有这么多耳目监视
There are eyes, ears,
根本不可能与外面联系
dots that couldn't be connected from the outside.
-那英格力士  费兹  博西   -正是计划的一部分
-And English, Fitz or Percy?  -One of those dots.
那你究竟想怎么搞定这些事
And how exactly are you supposed to pull this off?
我的朋友会帮助我的
With a little help from my friends.
苏克雷  等一下
Sucre, hold up.
斯科菲尔德  有人要见你
Scofield, you've got company.
为什么我总觉得你有事瞒着我呢   斯科菲尔德
Why do I get the feeling that there's more to you than meets the eye, Scofield?
有什么事想说的吗
Anything you wanna tell me?
你进来的原因  除了抢银行之外
Some other reason you're in here besides holding up a bank?
-你会被转走  -什么
-You're being transferred.  -What?
你会被转移到 斯特斯维尔
We're moving you over to Statesville.
-你不能这么做  -不 我能
-You can't do that.  -Yes, I can.
我是这儿的头 这儿我说了算
I'm the boss here.This is my house.
-我要三个星期的时间  -什么
-Three weeks.  -What for?
林肯・布伦斯
Lincoln Burrows.
三周后他将被处决
He's being executed in three weeks.
恩  这个我知道 可这儿和你有什么关系
I'm aware of that. What's that to you?
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
当我知道我要被判刑
When I knew I was being sent to prison,
我的律师就请求监狱总局
my attorney petitioned the DOC.
-这样你就能和他在一起了  -没错
-So you could be near him.  -That's right.
别把我转走
Don't take that away from me.
至少在这一切都结束前
Not until it's over.
不是我想转走你的
I'm not the one behind the transfer.
你的对头是比我还要高的人物
You're up against much bigger fish than me.
我会安排你们互相再见的
I'll arrange for you to say goodbye.
明天就走吧
You ship out tomorrow.
我打算今晚动手  看看是否能到屋顶
I'm going into the walls,see if I can access the roof.
不想说说转监狱的事么
You going to tell me about the transfer?
-我会处理的  -你会处理
-I'm taking care of it.  -You're taking care of it?
听起来你已经搞定了
Sounds to me like you're reaching.
也许  有些进展
Maybe. A little.
有些进展
A little.
你知道嘛   本来我已经准备接受这一切了
You know, I had made my peace to what was coming.
但你出现了 给了我一样东西
and then you show up and give me the one thing
是我这种人不应该有的东西
a man in my situation shouldn't have.
希望
Hope.
但似乎又要被夺走了
And now that's gonna be taken away.
-别这么想  林肯  -我只有三周的时间了
-Don't do this, Linc.  -I got three weeks.
你想让我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
说阿 迈克尔
Come on, Michael.
你到底想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
带她回来
Bring her back.
你知道我做不到
You know I can't do that.
听着  有些事情我的确可以做
But, look, there's some stuff that I can do.
虽然一切都不一样了 不过我们会想办法的
It's not gonna be the same,but we're gonna figure it out.
而且  不管发生什么 我们永远在一起
And no matter what,it's still gonna be me and you.
好吧  但如果你出事儿了怎么办
OK, but what if something happens to you?
你只要 相信我就可以了
You just have a little faith.
相信我就可以了
Just have a little faith.
好吧  就算这样
All right, here's the deal.
我们相信林肯 这录影带是伪造的
We believe Lincoln,this tape is a lie.
-肯定是的  -你都看到了  都在这儿了
-It has to be.  -you saw it. It's all there.
恩  也许我们要找的不是这个
Yeah, but, but maybe what we're looking for is what's not there.
好吧  斯蒂德曼
OK. Steadman.
-你瞧 他在看什么  -车 还是什么人
You see, what's he looking at?  -car? A pedestrian?
不  不  不 你看他的视线太高了  不是吗
No,No,No. His eye line is too high, right?
看起来他更像是在看摄像头
It's like he's looking right into the camera.
可能还在说 茄子
Might as well be saying "cheese."
可现在他就坐那儿而已
Now he just sits there.
像这样待了十  十五秒左右  看起来他在...
Like,10, 15 seconds, as if he was...
等人
Waiting for someone.
这里
There.
那可是一把九毫米口径的手枪
That's a nine millimetre.
难道不该有点后坐力什么的吗
Shouldn't there be some kind of kick or something?
林肯身体很壮实
Lincoln's pretty strong.
难道壮到可以消除任何后坐力么
Yeah, but strong enough to bury a recoil?
假设  你杀了人
Now, you shoot someone,
如果光为了复仇
supposedly for revenge.
你还会花时间返回来
do you take the time to go back in
翻箱倒柜的  还不赶紧离开吗
and hit the glove box? Or get the hell out of there?
他们说他想造成一个抢劫的假象
Feds said he was trying to make it look like a robbery.
看着
Look.
看到林肯离开摄像头的角度没有
Look at Lincoln's angle as he leaves the frame.
远离车的方向走去的
walks away from the car.
但现在这家伙
Now, this guy,
故意没有让自己的脸被摄像头捕捉到
who conveniently hides his face from the camera
那他为什么还要返回呢  为什么
he comes back in. Why?
正好能解释在他公寓里发现的 那条带血的裤子
To explain the bloody pants they'd already planted in his apartment.
-尼克 这太棒了  -恩
-Nick, this is great.  -Yeah
-我们该去找谁  -现在谁都不找
-Who shall we go to?  -Nobody.
我是说  从公正的角度看
Yet,I mean,to the unbiased eye,
我们正从死神边缘抢夺时间
we're just backing a horse that died in the gate.
有很多不确定的因素  你知道的
A lot of "what ifs" and conjecture, you know.
我们什么都没有 我们需要证据
We don't have anything. We need some evidence.
瞧  如果  林肯没开那枪
Look, if Lincoln didn't fire this gun,
那一定有个非常专业的人
then somebody with some serious skills went to
伪造了这盘带子来证明他开了那枪
work on this to prove he did.
恩  那我们怎么证明呢
Fine, but how do we prove that?
我认识一个人
I know a guy.
-你认识一个人   -是的  我知道
-You know a guy?  -Yeah, I know a guy.
谢谢
Thanks.
看来我们得再做次讨论
Seems we need to have another powwow.
听说你正在整理你的行李
There's been talk about you packing your bags.
别听信谣言
Don't believe everything you hear.
我哪儿都不会去
I'm not going anywhere.
你知道  我真的很难相信你
You know, I have a really hard time trusting you, fish.
重要的是我们仍然按计划进行着
The important thing is that we stay on schedule.
-英格力士 费兹 或者 博西   -英格力士 费兹 或者 博西
-And English, Fitz and Percy?  -English, Fitz or Percy.
你想知道我会怎么选么
You want to know which one we should take out?
没别的意思 不过我不需要你的建议
all due respect, I don't need opinions.
我得知道答案
I need answers.
记住  监狱长晚上五点离开
Remember, The warden leaves at five tonight,
所以五点零五分之前 我们得拿到钥匙
so by five past five we're going to need that key.
有了钥匙 你怎么能得到答案呢
And how is this key gonna give you the answers?
我会考虑这个问题的
I'll worry about that.
你的问题是拿到钥匙
You,Worry about getting the key.
这把钥匙最好能有所值  明白吗
This key better be worth it. Understand?
下午好  斯科菲尔德 先生
Afternoon, Mr Scofield.
我想知道怎么才能不被转移
I need to know if there's any way to block a transfer order.
-至少有五十种方法  -那好
-There's about 50 ways.  -All right.
我要那种最快的
I'll take the quickest.
你写份申请来获取所谓的 临时禁令
You file a motion for what they call an "interlocutory injunction."
-这需要多久   -你能多快写完
-How long does that take?  -How fast can you write?
人们可以声称任何东西都有 可能损害到他们的合法权益
A man can claim almost anything violates his constitutional rights.
像环境问题  过敏反应
There's environmental issues, allergies,
宗教需要等  你可以选个适合你自己的
religious requirements, take your pick.
-如果他们不接受怎么办   -没关系
-What if they don't buy it?  -Don't matter.
法律规定 法院必须接收你的申请
Court's required by law to hear your motion
那样在他们受理之前 你就不允许被转移
Until they do, you can't be transferred.
那帮该死的想把我这把老骨头转走 已经动了十年的心思了
Hell, they've been trying to move my tired, grey behind for ten years.
上帝保佑美国的司法系统
God bless the American legal system.
为什么你那么想留在这儿呢
Why do you want to stay in here so badly?
这儿有我不能丢下的东西
someone here I can't bear to leave behind.
我想我们在某种程度上是一致的
I guess that means we've got something in common.
政府要给 林肯・布伦斯 做次体检
State's requiring a physical for Burrows.
-你听说了吧   -谢谢
-You heard the news? didn't you?  -Thanks.
听说什么
No, what?
-他们是兄弟  -谁
-They're brothers.  -Who?
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德
Burrows and Scofield.
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield?
从监狱长那儿的狱警那里听到的
Heard it from one of the COs over in Gen Pop.
他没跟你提起这事儿么
He didn't say anything to you about it?
没有
No.
恩  离自己的哥哥这么近
Oh. Must be hard to be here so close to your brother
却对此无能为力 他一定很痛苦
and not be able to do anything to help him.
-这是什么东西   -一些厕所读物
-What's this?  -More bathroom reading.
-又是 韦斯特莫兰德 写的   -斯科菲尔德
Westmoreland again?  -Scofield.
他好像不想被转走
He's blocking his transfer.
即便申请被拒绝 至少也得花三十天处理
Even if the motion is denied,it's gonna take 30 days to process.
也就是说
And that means...
好了  我得进去了
All right, I'm going in.
-我需要你的帮助  -你是指在墙里面
-I'm gonna need your help.  -You mean In ?
就现在   我想你该等等
Now? I thought you were waiting till...
我必须确认一下 我怎么才能上到那儿
I need to make sure I know how I'm getting up there
那么到时候
so when the time comes...
好像你没注意到 所有的灯都亮着
In case you didn't notice, the lights are all on.
我们会被很多人看到的
You've got a live studio audience, fish.
你想搞得众人皆知么
How are you gonna get around that?
我们不是还有衣服要洗吗
Don't we have some laundry to do?
事先声明
Just to be clear,
我可不高兴碰你的内裤
I ain't touching your drawers.
眼睛朝前看
Eyes straight ahead.
别停下
Keep it moving.
别停下  继续走
Keep it moving. Keep it moving.
抓住他   抓住他
Get him up. Hit him.
嫩鸡
Fish.
我可应付不过来
I can't deal with that.
嫩鸡 赶快啊
Fish. Come on.
嘿 嫩鸡
Yo, fish.
嫩鸡  你去的时间太长了
Fish, you're taking too long, bro.
这可不行  伙计
This ain't gonna fly.man.
作为波多黎各人
The Ricans,
我们天生就有高血压的  你知道不
we've got genetically higher blood pressure, you know that?
我堂兄  就是因为压力过大才死的
My cousin, he died from too much stress.
好像你说过 是你的堂兄抢了你女朋友吧
Thought you said your cousin was moving in on your girl.
那是另外一个 不过还真谢你的提醒呢  混蛋
That's my other cousin, but thanks for bringing that up, jackass.
听着  有好消息 我知道怎么到屋顶了
Look, the good news is I can get to the roof.
-那现在怎么办呢   -现在 就等合适的时机了
-So what happens now?  -Now?It's all about timing.
这可是高技术含量的东西  你知道会是谁做的吗
This is a top-dollar job.Do you know who did it?
不知道 你呢
No. Do you?
能够做出这种活儿的都是魔鬼了  伙计
People who do this kind of work are ghosts, man.
高手背后的高手阿
The guy behind the guy behind the guy,
-你知道我的意思么   -你发现什么吗
-you know what I mean?  -You see anything?
被剪辑过的痕迹 证明这是被伪造的
Definitive cuts? Any place that proves the tape might've been doctored?
做的很漂亮 没有任何痕迹
The thing's clean. No footprints.
我是说  通常  如果你把片子分成几层的话
I mean, usually, you peel a video back a couple of layers
伪造的痕迹就显露出来了  但现在什么你们瞧  都看不出来
and anything bogus comes off.  Now you see it, now you don't.
但这盘带子不同
But not this one.
肯定是处理过的 但很巧妙
It's laced. Ingrained.
-你发现什么了   -没
-You see something?  -No
问题就处在你们的眼睛上 他们正是利用这个欺骗了你
The problem with eyes is they play tricks on you..
但是你的耳朵  它不会欺骗你
But your ears...ears don't lie.
瞧  这是从带子分离出来的音频
Here's the audio track from the tape.
-听起来跟真的一样  是吧   -恩
-Sounds pretty true?  -Yeah.
不过声音是假的 声音不应该这样消失的
But noise is a lie .See, it doesn't just die like that.
应该是逐渐消失 所以声音应该是跳跃性的
Stripped down,those levels should be dancing.
我的意思是 在那种地方的枪声
I  mean, a room that size would give you a..
应该是一种   砰 砰 砰 砰
a... blam, blam, blam, blam. You know?
明白吗    声波应该是逐渐从每个墙上消失
Like, one off each wall, split second after the other.
而你们给的带子上 回声是同时响起的
On yours,the reverb's bouncing at the same time.
-这到底是什么意思   -枪声的声波
-What does that mean?  -The sound of a gunshot.
并不是从案发现场录的
It wasn't recorded in that room.
你能确信么
Would you testify to that?
恩  我   不知道 毕竟你们给我的是录制的
Oh, uh, I don't know. The tape's a dupe.
你知道  据我所知 你们都动过带子
You know, for all I know, you guys tampered with it.
听着  如果想让我到法庭作证
Look, you want me to testify in court,
我要得到原始带子才行
I'm gonna need to get my hands on the original.
-过敏反应怎么样了  -你说什么
-How are those allergies?  -Excuse me?
在你的报告里  你提到了  嗯
In your motion, you cited chronic...
鼻窦炎
Sinusitis.
可这并不属于过敏 事实上  只是一种细菌感染
It's not an allergy, actually.It's a bacterial infection.
从东墙河边飘来的空气
The moist air from the river along the east wall
让我感觉  你知道的
helps keep me, you know...
很好
clear.
我很惊讶
I'm impressed.
你到这儿还不到一周 就变得如此圆滑
Not even a week here and you're working it like an old con.
哦  这方面你比我厉害多了 监狱长大人
Well, you've got one up on me, Warden.
你知道我为什么要写那份申请
You know why I needed to file those motions,
但我很迷惑 为什么你要转移我
but I have no idea why you needed to transfer me.
人流管制  斯科菲尔德 就这样  很简单
Traffic control, Scofield.That's all.
人流控制
Traffic control.
瞧  快到五点了 今天就到这儿了怎么样
It's coming up on five o'clock. What do you say we call it a day?
-恐怕我做不完了 先生  -为什么
-I don't think I can do that.  -Why not?
如果我现在撤 这个会倒下来的
If I let go of this support right now,the whole thing's coming down.
瞧  泰姬陵是用的轴向力
See, the Taj was designed using axial force
一系列沿着一个轴的力
a series of internal forces along the longitudinal axis.
嗯  那要多久呢
Yeah. How much longer?
这就要看什么时候干了
Depends on how long it takes to dry.
如果你要我走 我可以告诉你秘书怎么扶住它
If you need me to leave,I can show your secretary how to hold it.
好吧  你可以留在这儿直到它干
You can stay till it dries.
门外会有警卫
There'll be a guard waiting outside the door.
你做完了就和 贝克 说一声
Just check in with Becky when you're done
他会安排人送你回去
and she'll have somebody escort you back to your cell.
-好的  -还有  嗯  斯科菲尔德
-All right.  -And, Scofield.
很感谢你今天能来
I wanna thank you for showing up today.
如果你不来  我也能理解的
I would've understood it if you didn't.
-我们说定的不是嘛  -嗯
-We had a deal.  -Right.
还是要谢谢你
Still, thanks.
我妻子看到这个会非常喜欢的
My wife is gonna love it.
不客气
You're welcome.
明天见  先生
See you tomorrow, sir.
晚安  监狱长先生
Good night, Warden.
我们正巧是两个人 又碰巧彼此认识
We'd just happen to be two people who happen to know each other,
一起出现在同一家戏剧院
who happen to show up at the same movie theatre
还是同一个时间
at what happens to be the same time.
是么
That's it.
你知道  从这个角度看上去
You know, from this angle,
你还是和我们刚认识时一样漂亮
you look just as good as you did when we first met.
-这样呢   -更美了
-How about from this one?  -Even better.
是给你那些客人的
Those are for your guests.
-客人   -不是你的同事吗
-Guests?  -Your associates.
他们说你在开会 所以先在里面等
They said you had a meeting.They're in the den.
晚上好  监狱长先生
Evening, Warden.
我也无能为力了
There's nothing I can do.
我必须按照法律 把那些申请提交法庭
I'm legally obligated to file every properly drafted motion with the court
以便于听证会安排
so a hearing can be scheduled.
要花多长时间
And how long does that take?
至少要一个月 如果不顺利  还有可能更长
A month, maybe two if there's a logjam
很抱歉  不过这不归我管
I'm sorry, but it's out of my hands.
为什么我感觉你好像无所谓的样子
Why do I feel you're not all that disappointed?
我能问个问题吗  监狱长
May I ask you a question, Warden?
只是据我观察而已
More of an observation, really.
我刚看了那张照片  嗯
I was looking at the morgue photos
就是那个男孩的照片   叫 威尔・克雷顿 是吧
from that boy back in Toledo ,Will Clayton
和他爸爸还真像
and, my Lord,if he wasn't the spitting image of his daddy.
感觉就像苹果从很高的树上掉下来  是吧
apple fell real far from the tree with that one, didn't it?
从苹果树上掉下来 血肉模糊
fell off the tree, fell all over the pavement.
你这个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
你的妻子看来原谅你了
Your wife gave you a pass on the affair,
但是应该是最后的底线了吧
Something tells me that's pretty much all the forgiveness she's got left in her bag.
特别是碰到私生子的时候
Especially when it comes to an illegitimate child.
小威尔是怎么了
What happened with young Will,
监狱长先生
Warden?
给我滚出去
Get out of my house.
赶紧处理掉 斯科菲尔德 的申请
Lose Scofield's paperwork.
你们要留下来一起吃晚餐么
You gentlemen staying for dinner?
谢谢了  不过我想我们该走了
Thanks, but I think we're on our way.
朱迪  谢谢你的招待
Judy, it was a real pleasure.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是我喝到的最好的冰红茶了
And that just may have been the best iced tea I've ever had.
监狱长先生 真的应该好好珍惜现在的一切
Warden, better do everything you can to hold on to this one.
-我会的  -很好
-I will.  -Good.
没事儿吧你
Is everything all right?
嗯  很好  别担心
Oh, yeah. Just fine. honey..
只是有些未做完的工作而已
I just have a little unfinished work to take care of.
我马上出去吃饭
I'll be right in.
好的
OK.
都搞定了
It's all clear.
晚上好  林肯
Evening, Lincoln.
医生  你来啦
Doctor.
我今晚得给你做个体检
I'm supposed to give you a physical this evening.
整个过程可能会比较繁琐
apologize in advance for the heavy dose of irony we're about to participate in.
没关系  你也是例行公事
That's all right. Just doing your job.
嗯  让政府知道你现在很健康
Yeah, well...Letting them know you're healthy enough to execute
不过这可不是我从医的初衷
is not why I went to medical school.
-很抱歉  -没关系
-I apologise.  -It's OK.
好了
All right.
嗯  我得了解下你的家族病史
I'm gonna need a family medical history from you.
看看有没有遗传性的疾病
Any ailments or conditions that are hereditary.
先从你母亲开始吧
start with your mom.
-癌症 肝癌  -好的 你父亲呢
-Cancer. Liver.  -OK. Father?
嗯  我小时候就分开了
Split when I was young.
兄妹呢
Siblings.
除了迈克尔还有别人吗
Anyone besides Michael?
这儿可不大  林肯
Fox River's a small town, Lincoln.
在这儿人们有足够多的时间闲聊
People around here don't have a whole lot to do besides time and talk.
你们关系怎么样  很亲密吧
you close?
以前是的
We were.
-现在呢   -嗯
-How about now?  -Huh?
现在关系怎么样呢
How about now?
他的一生很惨
He has been abandoned his whole life
父亲很早就抛弃他  母亲也走了 现在又轮到我
Dad, Mom ,she died young,and now me.
所以就到这儿来了
Think that's why he's here?
是否你的
Cos your
你的死会再次勾起他的回忆
your death would feel like it's happening again
我很早就离开他了
I abandoned him a long time ago.
这就是他为什么会进监狱的原因吧
That's why he's here.
威尔  十岁
关门
Gates closing.
-是时候了  -什么
-It's time.  -Time?
哦  天哪  我们又得忙活开了
Oh, God. Here we go again.
十五分钟后就得点名 你到底想干吗
Count's in 15 minutes. What are you doing?
相信我  知道得越少对你越好
Trust me. The less you know, the better.
我知道的越少  伙计  我可还什么都不知道呢
The less I know? Man,You got me in the dark.
这样才好啊
That's exactly where you wanna be.
这个时间很少看到你嘛
Don't normally find you here at this hour.
是来忏悔  还是需要神的建议
Are you seeking his forgiveness? Or advice?
我也不清楚  本
I really don't know any more, Ben.
我知道我应该为我儿子的事负责的
All I know is my son Will was my responsibility.
我要是不走 也许他就不会出事儿
If I'd stayed in his life, I could've saved his life.
他的死只是个意外  亨利
His death was an accident, Henry.
虽然他是个罪犯  还吸毒
He was a criminal,and an addict
但他毕竟只有十八岁啊
but he was only 18 years old.
可他母亲说的很清楚 如果想和她在一起
His mother made it clear you couldn't be in his life
你就得离开你儿子
if you weren't gonna be in hers.
你既然选择跟朱迪在一起 你就应该了解这些
When you chose to stay with Judy,you understood that.
我不仅想到了 而且很感激
I not only understood it, I was grateful for it.
我告诉自己
I told myself
我尊重了她的意愿
I was respecting her wishes.
虽然我很恨她
I cursed her
但每天我还是感谢上帝
under my breath while every day I thanked God
让我从这件事里面
for allowing me to wash my hands of...
解脱出来
Of Toledo.
为了所有这一切
All of it.
所以  我回到朱迪身边
So I ran home,to Judy,
把秘密埋藏心底
I buried the secret.
但我却连
But I never got a chance to...
亲手埋葬
to bury my...
自己儿子的机会都没有
my son.
我算是什么样的人啊 本
What kind of a person does that, Ben?
为了自己的利益就不顾及别人的性命
Sacrifices somebody else's life just to make their own life easier.
你们可以整晚和我争论
You can argue with me all night.
我真的无能为力了
Believe me,I haven't got anything better to do.
但我确实不能把作为证据的原始带给你们
But it won't change the fact that I can't just hand out original copies of evidence.
哪怕你就看一眼
If you could just take a look...
哦  你就是有司法部长的签名都不行
Oh, I don't care if your FOIL is signed by the attorney general,
我还是不能给你们
I can't give it to you.
那我们是否可以带人过来 在现场看一下呢
What if we brought somebody here to watch it?
你们可以派人盯着他
Your supervisor could monitor him the entire time.
可以搜身  或者发誓
He'd strip down and swear on a stack of Bibles.
-怎样做都可以  -等等 你们要的文件编号多少
-Whatever it takes.  -Wait, what did you say the docket number was?
嗯  是 296-SPE
It's 296-SPE
有什么问题么
What's wrong?
跟我来
Come with me.
昨晚  一根水管爆裂 淹了整间房间
Last night a pipe burst upstairs,flooded the place.
一百多个案子的档案
Files from over 100 cases
可能大部分都没了  包括你们要的
pretty much lost all of them, including yours.
-只冲了这间房子?   -谁说得清呢 灾难
-Just this room?  -Some kind of freak accident.
-点名  -克林汉姆
-Count'em.  -Callahan..
马里若夫斯基  伯莱恩
Malinowski, Pohlen.
查恩斯  格拉齐亚诺
Chance, Graziano.
斯科菲尔德  苏克雷
Scofield, Sucre.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield,
快给我出来
get the hell out here.
有人越狱
We got a runner.
好吧  再问你一遍  小鸡巴
All right. For the last time, pini Ata.
斯科菲尔德 到底到哪儿去了
Where the hell's Scofield?
如果他跑了  你就不会好过  懂不
He's gone, you're gone. You hear me?
取消警报吧  队长
Call it off, Captain.
-我知道斯科菲尔德在哪儿  -哪儿
-I got Scofield right here.  -Where?
在监狱长办公室呢
In the warden's office.
你亲眼看见的
you looking at him?
别光泡马子了 到里面去看看
Stop trying to nail the secretary.and check the damn office.
队长  他跑了
Captain, he's gone.
英格力士街
博西街
费兹街
-他不可能就这样蒸发掉的  -明白  先生
-man can'tjust vanish.deputy.  -I know, sir.
-他从来没出来过么   -没有
-He never checked out?  -No.
-那后门呢   -我查过了 锁着呢
-and the rear door?  -It's still locked, sir. I checked.
那他到底是
How the hell did he...?
出什么事儿了
What's going on?
你在这里待的太久了
You're in the warden's office after hours.
我可以现在就杀了你 不用负任何责任
I could kill you and the paperwork wouldn't need more than a date.
-告诉我  你究竟在这儿干吗   -好了  行了
-Tell me, what were you doing in here?  -All right, Deputy. That's enough.
胶水还没干呢  是你让我留在这儿的
work wasn't dry.You said to stay until it was.
-你一直待在这儿的么   -是的  先生
-You were in here?  -Yes, sir.
是的  我没看到他出去过
-It's true. I never saw him leave.
可能我没注意他在桌子后面呢
I must not have seen him behind the table.
监狱长  这一切简直太荒唐了
Warden, all due respect, this is ridiculous!
犯人居然不在牢房里
This prisoner was out of his cell.
-还错过了点名  -我知道了 副官
-He missed the count.  -I understand, Deputy.
事实是 现在 斯科菲尔德 已经不再是问题了
thing is,Mr Scofield is not our problem any more.
看起来他的档案出了些问题
Seems there was an error in his paperwork.
马上他就得被转移了
He's gonna be transferred after all.
这不可能
That's not possible.
把犯人押回牢房去
Escort the prisoner back to his cell.
狱长  我只需要三周而已
Warden, all I need is three weeks.
-放开我  -嘿  快点
-Get off me!  -Hey, come on, now!
求你了  我只需要一点时间
please. I just need a little time.
就一点点时间而已
Just give me the time.
你觉得那仅仅是个巧合吗
Any chance you want to write this off as a coincidence?
我也不这么认为
Me neither.
他们怎么会知道我们要那盘带子
How could they have known we were coming for the tape?
三小时前 我们还不认识呢
Three hours ago, we didn't even know.
也许  我们得罪人了
Well,We're pissing someone off.
似乎你还很开心
You say that like it's a good thing.
有人在妨碍司法公正 不过我们还得有信心
People start breaking the law,you know you're getting warm.
我们手上还有复制的  也许
We still have our copy of the tape, so maybe...
-尼克  -待这别动
-Nick.  -Stay here.
不知道是谁  已经走了
Whoever it was has gone.
-有东西丢了么   -没有
-Does it look like they got anything?  -No.
好像什么都没动过
Everything's exactly the way I left it.
怎么啦   怎么啦
What? What?
怎么啦
What?
-带子没了  -你确定吗
-The tape. It's gone.  -Are you sure?
-他们怎么知道   -我们得冷静地想想
-How could they know?-Think this through.
他们怎么知道带子就放在这儿
How could they know exactly where to look?
等等  还有其他人有这儿的钥匙么
Wait. Does anyone else have a key?
-你确定是放这儿的么   -当时你也在啊  记得么
-Are you sure this is where you put it?  -You were here, remember?
我当时跟你说话  然后就走到这儿了
I was talking to you, I walked toward the cabinet,
然后我说
and I said...
怎么了
What?
维罗妮卡
Veronica,
没事儿吧
are you OK?
维罗妮卡
Veronica.
开门
Open up!
早餐时间  都出来
Breakfast, gentlemen. Let's move it.
苏克雷  走吧 斯科菲尔德  你留在这儿
Sucre, let's go. Scofield, wait here.
估计马上就会把你送走
I'm sure your ride'll be along any minute now.
不应该这样
This can't be it.
事情不能就这样结束
It can't end like this.
快点出来
Let's move it.
-费兹街   -什么
-Fitz.  -What?
我们可以从费兹街逃走
We were gonna take Fitz out.
毫无疑问
It was as clear as day.
警察呢  他们多久会到
And the cops? How long did it take them to respond?
你都算过了
You got all the timing down?
我们有足够时间
Think we would've made it?
苏克雷  快点
Sucre, now.
嘿 嫩鸡  你到哪儿去
Hey, fishface, where are you going?
打电话给我妻子  告诉她带着孩子离开这个国家
Call my wife. Tell her to get the kids and get the hell out of the country.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别忘了系安全带
Don't forget to buckle up.
这个犯人在这里干吗啊
What's this prisoner doing out of his cell?
-要被转移  -不 不 不 不
-being transferred.  -No,no,no,no,
肯定有些误会
There must be some kind of a mistake.
他昨天才提交了份申请
This man filed a motion yesterday.
他身体有问题 不适合现在被转送
He has a medical condition which precludes transfer.
-鼻窦炎 是吧   -鼻窦炎
-Sinusitis, right?  -Sinusitis.
把他送回牢房去
Take the prisoner back to his cell.
但得扣放风时间 他昨晚没有点名
But yank his rec time. He missed count last night.
回来的好早 你没事儿吧
You're home early. Everything OK?
是啊
Yeah.
恩  没什么
Yeah, it is.
只是  嗯
There's just...
朱迪
Judy,
我要和你说一个人
there's someone I need to tell you about.
喂
Yes?
-转监狱没有能够成功    -真令人失望
-The transfer did not go through.   -That's disappointing.
-我们可以再次提出  但那个狱长   -别再浪费时间了
-We can refile, but the warden...   -It's a waste of time.
我想我们别尽做些表面文章了  先生们
I think it's time we stopped beating around the bush,gentlemen,
是时候动手了
and go after the damn bush.
布伦斯
Burrows.
你想让我做什么
What do you want done?
夺走他现在惟一还拥有的东西...时间
Take the only thing Burrows has left...time.
死刑不一定非得通过监狱里的电椅来执行
After all, the chair isn't the only way to take a man's life in prison.
为什么牙膏筒却没事?
how come they can't eat through the tube?